Schultz; Harry E., Jr; Papers mss145
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Harry E. Schultz, Jr. Papers
1913-2000
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
mss145
4.21 cubic ft.
The collection contains a significant amount of material pertaining to the Delaware and Hudson Railroad (D&H) where Harry E. Schultz, Jr. was employed as a civil engineer for more than 40 years.
Content Description
This collection consists of Delaware and Hudson Railroad (D&H) memos regarding operations and maintenance and clearance; blueprints and schematics; photographs, including albums containing images of stations along the D&H Railroad lines - Saratoga Division (1913), Champlain Division (1914 and ca. 1925), City of Albany Improvements (1913), Susquehanna Division (ca. 1925); slides; manuals and guides; pamphlets; postcards; track maps; and D&H memorabilia.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized alphabetically. There are no series.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Elizabeth Barry, daughter of Harry E. Schultz, Jr., donated all materials in this collection to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives in 2021.
Access
Access to this collection is unrestricted.
Biographical Note
Harry E. Schultz, Jr. was born in 1922 in Albany, N.Y. and raised in nearby Colonie. He attended Union College. Schultz was employed by the Delaware & Hudson Railroad (D&H) as a civil engineer for 41 years. He rose from an entry level position in North Creek and retired in 1983 as assistant chief engineer of the company. During his career he was stationed in North Creek, Saratoga, Plattsburgh, and Albany. His work often required him to travel to Binghamton, Scranton, and Wilkes-Barre, Pa.
Following Schultz's retirement, he worked for several local contractors as a consultant engineer. He was a lifetime member of the American Railway Engineering Association. Schultz passed away in July 2007 and was survived by his wife of 58 years, Ann M. Keon Schultz, four children, and seven grandchildren.
Schultz, Harry E., Jr. (1922-2007); Delaware and Hudson Railway Company; Delaware and Hudson Railroad Corporation; Business and Industry; Railways; City planning--New York (State)--Albany; Slides (photographs); Photograph albums; Railroad stations
- Aboriginal Place Names of Present Railroad Stations, 1947 (Flat-file 1)
- American Railway Engineering Association, 1962-1963 (Flat-file 2)
- Association of American Railroads, 1960-1966 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Bethlehem Steel Company: How to Attach a Wire Rope Socket, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Boston and Maine Railroad, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Champlain Transportation Company Centenary Booklet, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence with Image: Dudley Bierau, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- D&H: Agreement Between the D&H and the Brotherhood of Maintenance of Way Employees, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- D&H: Blueprints, Schematics, and Plans, 1922-1951; Undated (Flat-file 3)
- D&H: Blueprints, Schematics, and Plans, 1931-1940; 1975-1981; 2000 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- D&H: Blueprints, Schematics, and Plans, 1935-1967; Undated (Flat-file 4)
- D&H: Blueprints, Schematics, and Plans, 1940; 1947-1948 (Flat-file 5)
- D&H: Bridge Load Chart, 1947 (Flat-file 6)
- D&H: Bridges and Weight Data, 1959-1965 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- D&H: Clearances and Bridge Restrictions, 1931-1971 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- D&H: Employment Bulletins, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- D&H: Formulas and Misc. Data, 1933-1985 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- D&H Handwritten Notes and Sketches, 1960-1969 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- D&H: Instructions for the Operation of Track Cars Booklet, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- D&H: Joint Official Lists, 1957-1963 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- D&H: The Leaf Peeker's Special, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- D&H: Locomotive Crane Data, 1932-1983 (Flat-file 7)
- D&H: Luggage Sticker, Undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
- D&H: Newsletter, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- D&H: Operations Memoranda, 1934-1938 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- D&H: Operations Memoranda, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- D&H: Org Chart, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- D&H: Photo Album - Albany Improvement, 1913 (Oversize 1)
- D&H: Photo Album - Champlain Division Station Buildings, 1925 (Oversize 2)
- D&H: Photo Album - Champlain Division Stations, 1913 (Oversize 1)
- D&H: Photo Album - Saratoga Division Stations, 1913 (Oversize 3)
- D&H: Photo Album - Susquehanna Division Station Buildings, 1925 (Oversize 2)
- D&H: Photos, Undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
- D&H: Postcards, 1951-1975 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- D&H: Sesquicentennial Special Booklet, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- D&H: Sisson vs D&H Memo, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- D&H: Standard Plans, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- D&H: Station Photos and Layouts, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- D&H: Trackwork, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- D&H: Turntable Maintenance Instructions, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Fiber Rope Safe Practices Pamphlet No. 6, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- FRA Track Safety Standards, 1972-1982 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Fracturometer, Undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
- How to Travel By Train, Undated (Box 1, Folder 32)
- K + E Solar Ephemeris, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Local Climatological Data, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Manila and Wire Rope Safe Practice Pamphlet No. 26, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- New AREA Specification Guide for Railroad Track Tools, Undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Newspaper Clippings and Copies, 1973-1990 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Newsletters of the Mohawk & Hudson Chapter, NRHS, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Pennsylvania Public Utility Commission, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Pennsylvania Railroad Company, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Photo of Whitehall Station, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Photos, 1942-1943; 1949 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Photos, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Photos, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Photos, Undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
- A Pocket Guide to Pettibone Railroad, Undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Portec Model MC Rail & Flange Lubricator Manual, Undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Public Works Hauling Permits, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  General
  /
- Rail Defect Manuals, 1964; 1989 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Railroad Vegetation Management, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Railway Age Weekly, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Railway Engineering and Maintenance Magazine: How Long Rails?, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- The Railway Gazette: Long Welded Rails, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Reading Company Track Maps, 1970 (Flat-file 8)
- REMSA's Annual Banquet Program, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Safe Worker, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Scaffolds -Safe Practices Pamphlet No. 12, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Slides, 1956; 1959 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Slides, 1965; 1967; 1973 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Slides, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Slides, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Slides, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Slides, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Slides, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Slides, 1981; 1983-1984; 1986 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Slides, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Slides, Undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Slides: Schenectady Railroad, 1975-1985 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Track Safety Standards - DOT, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Track Safety Standards Calculator, Undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Track Structure/Geometric Study, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 29)